A true story
本片根据真实事件改编
we are here.
我们抵达了
2438 meters attach.This is it, guys.
距离2438米，就是它，弟兄们
you got it, sam? roger.
-瞄准了吗，山姆？ -诺
If you get this I pay for the drinks.
搞定这事我请你喝个痛快
I get no bar inside with you,handsome.
我可不跟你去酒吧，靓仔
You confuse the ladies.
你可是中老年妇女的偶像
get the cameras, boys.I lit it like a Christmas.
瞄准，弟兄们，我要把它炸得跟大年三十晚上那样热闹
Bomber, you're in command.
轰炸机机组，听令
Bomber to pilot. rojer.
-驾驶员听令 -得令
Bomber to crew.
全体人员听令
Bomluiken opened.
投弹舱已经打开
Damn antiaircraft guns!
操他丫的高射炮！
Come on.
加油
Come on, Zamp.
大伙加油
There you are.
瞄准你了
Bombs dropped.
顺利投弹
Pilot, you can command. To Receive.
-驾驶员听令 -得令
Here we go.
咱们撒丫子撤吧
Yes, just like Christmas.
漂亮，真的跟过年放烟花一样
Bomluiken stuck.
投弹舱门卡住了
Zero, arriving aircraft for us.
零式战机！
Here they come.
鬼子来了！
Keep the doors closed, Zamp. To Receive.
-舱门关紧！ -收到！
Get them, Mitchell.
摆脱他们，米歇尔
About nine.
大概有九架零式！
Incoming three.
又有三架逼近
Turn them off, Mitchell.
甩掉他们，米歇尔
Among us.
我们被打中了
They're behind us.
他们正在尾随
Brooks, he is among us.You must go there.
布鲁克斯，那家伙追上来了，干死他！
Glassman?
格拉斯曼？
Let me look at you.
我帮你看看伤势
I know.You must be brave.
我知道，你一定要撑住啊！
You're still a handsome guy.I'm sick of you.
你依然是最棒的，振作点，别让我瞧不起你
I know.
我明白
I'm here. Hang on.I want to go home.
-我在这儿，挺住 -我想回家
You are going, Harry.Think of home.
你就快到家了，哈利，想想你的家
Take this here.
拿着！
Well done, guys.
打得好！弟兄们！
The back is shot to pieces. The hydraulic system is broken, but we fly.
-尾翼被打成了碎片 -液压系统损坏，不过咱们还能飞
We have no valves and therefore no braking.
没有阀门，因此没法制动
How far is it to the base? Five hours if we get that far.
-离基地还有多远？ -如果能撑得住的话，5个小时
The runway is almost 1829 meters long.We have 3048 meter is required without braking.
跑道大约1829米长，但不制动的话至少得3048米才行
God made two great lights.
上帝创造了两种伟大的光
The greater light to the day control, and the lesser light to govern the night.
至伟者用来掌控白昼，其次者
Light and darkness
光与暗
day and night are separated.
日与夜截然分开
God put everyone in place.
上帝让世界按规律运转
He wanted no war between the two.
他希望彼此没有战争
He said:"I have created them both."
上帝说：“二者皆朕造”
You have to live through the night
“宜于夜中生”
do not fight it.
“勿与黑暗争”
For God said:"The night is also mine."
上帝也曾曰过：“黑夜亦属朕”
He sent his son Jesus,not to drive a wedge.
上帝把儿子耶稣送下凡间，不是让他去挑拨离间
Not to make war against the sins of man.
不是向人类的罪恶发起战火
But to forgive them.Forgive their sins.
而是选择宽恕人类的罪恶
Smile for the sinner.
微笑面对罪恶的人类
Accept darkness.
拥抱黑暗
Live through the night.
生存在黑暗中
Love your enemy.
去爱喷你的喷子
I smell garlic now? What are you doing here?
-貌似闻到了大蒜的味道？ -你在这儿干嘛？
Return to Italy spaghetti and take your family with you.
怎么着？想跟你那恶心的一家回意大利去？
Lift it up.
架起来
Stay away from him.
放手！
Stay down Italian sucker.
给劳资好好趴着，意大利面条儿
Get him out.
把他拉开！
To Run.
快滚！
The only reason you're not stuck,because we take into account your parents.
要不是我们体谅你的父母，你早被玩死了
Everyone wants to have you gone.
每家每户都想让你滚犊子
Sorry, Louise.He fought again.
抱歉，露太太，他又打架了
We found this. He has painted,but it's just drink.
我们找到了这个，被他涂了油漆，其实是牛奶瓶子
Why So?
为什么这么做？
Why are you doing this?
你为什么要这样？
I do not know.
我不知道
How could you?
你好大的胆子！
What do you do to this family?
瞧瞧你给家里惹的祸！
They want us all here,and then you do this?
他们早就看我们不顺眼了，你倒搞这一出？
Want to go to jail?Why do you continue?
你想去坐牢吗？为什么死不悔改？
Go to your room.
滚回房间去
Care for my family.
请保佑我的家人
And beware my little Louie.
庇护我的小路
Come on, Jimmy.
跟上，杰米
Come on, Pete.
加油，皮特
Is anyone down there?Who's there?
下面有人吗？谁在下面？
This is really stupid.Since when are you so smart?
-真是个蠢主意 -你啥时候聪明过了？
Faster.Why So? No one follows me.
-再快点 -为毛？又没人追我跑
I follow you now.
我来追你
I can not.I'm not like you.
我做不到，大哥，我不如你
I'm a zero.Let me now but a zero.
我什么也不是，让我自生自灭吧
What are you talking about? I'm not at the track team.
-你胡说八道什么呢？ -我又不是田径队的
Yes, it can.If you can handle it, you get it.
你可以的，敢于实践，方能实现
What? If you can handle it, you get it.
-啥？ -敢于实践，方能实现
If you train harder and fight than the others ...
如果你拼命训练，超过别人
then you win.Then you walk past them.
那你就是老大，别人得跟在你后面
Whether you go on as before so you end up as a failure.
如果你自暴自弃，那你就永远是个屌丝
You can do it, Lou.You just have to believe in.
你可以的，小路，你要有信仰
I believe in nothing.
我没有信仰
I do.
我有
Come on.
来吧
Come on, Italian sucker.
加油，意大利面条儿！
Come on, Louie.
加油，路易！
What can run that boy.
那小子可真能跑
They call him:"Torrance Tornado."
人们叫他“托兰斯旋风”
It seems as if his feet do not touch the ground.
他蹭蹭蹭蹭，足不点地，如同凌波微步
Come on. Keep going.
加油！继续跑！
Come on, Louie.
加油！路易！
Come on.
加油！
Fr from Torrance Tornado ran the mile in four minutes, and 21.3 seconds.
“托兰斯旋风”1英里跑出了4分21.3秒！
Zamperini is officially the fastest runner in American history.
赞贝里尼正式成为美国历史上最快的长跑运动员
This boy is on the way to the Olympics.
这个年轻人正在踏向奥林匹克的圣殿
Why should I come. Yet you do not win. I know that.
-我有点自讨没趣，你又没赢 -我知道
The next Olympics I leave see it. This is just to practice.
下一届奥林匹克我要去看，这只是热身
Tokyo?
东京奥运会？
You're smart.Take care of yourself.
你很聪明，照顾好自己
Also make some fun.
也给自己找点乐子
Greeting the beautiful German girls for me. You know that.
-代我向最漂亮的德国姑娘们问好 -你懂的
Come here.
抱一个
Thanks, Pete.
谢谢你，大哥
For everything.
谢谢你为我做的一切
Go.
去吧
A moment of pain is worth lifelong glory.
刹那的痛苦值得换来终身的荣誉
Remember that.
记住了
Landing gear down. Here we go.
-放下起落架 -我们要降落了
We are approaching too fast.110 km / h.
我们速度太快了，110km/h了
Almost.
差不多了！
Still too fast. Come on.
-还是太快！ -走起！
Flat Tyre.
爆胎了
Thank you, God.
佛祖保佑
You are going to pray now?
你在祈祷？
I've been busy.
我一直都在祈的
My mother sometimes prays. There are many people who do it.
-我妈时不时也做祈祷 -很多人都做的
He says something back?
上帝有回话吗？
What?
-有 -说了什么？
He says I can not throw bombs.
他告诫我不要扔炸弹
Really?
真的假的？
Well, buddy.
很好，哥们
Right Now.
加速！
Come on, Louie.
加油，路易！
Come on, buddy.
加油，哥们！
Keep pushing.
继续加速！
Stop. And how much?
-好了！停！ -怎么样？多少？
4:12. You come close.
-啊哈！4分！ -4分12秒，又快了些
Hopefully you're not as fast in a sack.
希望你无论什么时候都能跑这么快
We have a mission.A rescue operation.
收拾行装，我们有任务了，一场飓风营救
A B24 Canton has not been reached.They probably are at sea.
一架B-24没有返航，可能掉海里了
The ocean is huge. Yes, and we have new crew members.
-海底捞针？ -是啊，还有，这几个弟兄是新成员
We have a new plane?
我们有新的飞机吗？
It's like sitting in the living room and the house trying to fly.
就像坐在客厅里，房子飘飘欲飞一样
They took the parts for other aircraft.Fortunately, we have the engine yet.
他们从别的飞机上取零件，很走运，搞到了引擎
According to Lieutenant was allowed to it in the air.
中尉允许我们
It was approved. By Helen Keller.
-再飞？ -由海兰·凯勒批准
The ocean is huge.
海洋太大了
Yes, enormous.
是的，浩瀚无垠
Mitchell, your turn.
米歇尔，到你了
So a duck walks into a bar.
讲个笑话，一只鸭子走进酒吧
Or rather staggering.
步履蹒跚的样子
He comes in and says to the bartender:"Give me a Creme de menthe."
他走进去跟酒保说：“我要薄荷甜酒”
Moment.First engine is off.
靠，一号引擎熄火
The others use more fuel.
其他的要用掉更多的燃料
I do not know.
-这个。。。。 -我不知道
engineer,You can take a look at the engine?
技师，看下发动机状况
What is happening? Call to the base.
-怎么了？ -呼叫基地
Which One? Left engine. Give more gas.
-哪个引擎？ -左引擎，加点燃料
Right engine more gas needed. They have enough.
-右引擎需要更多燃料 -右边应该够用的
Both lefthand motors are turned off.
玛德！左右引擎都熄火了！
Everything to the right, Phil
全力向右，菲尔！
Shall we? Get ready for the crash.
-看这样子是不是。。。。？ -恐怕要坠机了！
Gunner, grab the survival box.
炮手，放救生箱
Try the guns.
别管枪了
Who has the life raft? Glassman.
-救生艇！？ -格拉斯曼！
Who controls the raft? I.
-谁负责救生艇？ -我！
Distress Signal.Green Hornet here. We crash.
放呼救信号，这里是青蜂侠号，这里是青蜂侠号，有紧急情况，有紧急情况！
Everyone get ready.
大家听天由命吧
In a unique performance the black American Jesse Owens
简直了！丰功伟绩！美国黑人运动员杰西·欧文斯
four gold medals in the 100 meters, 200 meters
接连获得100米，200米
long jump and the 400 meter relay.
跳远和4*100米接力四块金牌！
So immediately starts the 5000 meter race, under the direction of Don Lash
接下来要进行的是5000米比赛，世界纪录保持者唐·拉什率领的美国队中
and debutant Louie Zamperini.
有一位超新星：路易·赞贝里尼
The runners are divided in three groups
选手们渐渐形成三个集团
Don Lash and the Finns:Salmin and Hackert in the lead.
唐·拉什和芬兰队的萨尔米，哈克特为第一集团
Finns are always a favorite long distance.
芬兰被称作“长跑之乡” ，中长跑是他们的传统
In the second group we the American Louie Zamperini.
第二集团的是美国队的路易·赞贝里尼
Finns: Hackert, Lehtin and Salmin still set the pace.
芬兰队的哈克特，雷霆和萨尔米继续当领头羊
Zamperini also falling behind.
赞贝里尼在后面紧追不舍
We go on to the eighth round.The Finns lead with Salmin in the first place.
现在进入第八圈，萨尔米率领的芬兰队依旧领先全场
Come on, Louie.
加油，路易
We start with the last round.The Finns lead.
比赛进入最后一圈，芬兰队仍保持着领先优势
Don Lash apparently does not the medal home to the US
唐·拉什看来很难为美国队争取到金牌了
Something happens behind.
场上形势出现了一些变化
Yes, Zamperini takes Norwegian Rolf Hansen.
瓦屋！是赞贝里尼！他超越了挪威队的罗夫·汉森
He apparently has a reserve tank.He really takes some time.
他开启了“副油箱模式”！他就像战斗机那样风驰电掣！这是他的成名绝技！
Hackert and Lehtinen are one and two,but look at that Zamperini.
哈克特和雷霆暂处一二位，但是让我们来关注赞贝里尼的表现！
He Don Lash in sight.
他逼近了唐·拉什！
Don Lash is not the first American,but high school boy Zamperini
看来第一个到达终点的美国人不会是唐·拉什了！而是高中男孩赞贝里尼！
Something I've never seen.
这是我从未见过的奇迹！
The record for the final round was 69.2 seconds.
在此之前5000米最后一圈的世界最好成绩是69.2秒！
Zamperini did there 56 seconds.
赞贝里尼刚才只用了56秒！！
That record remains still for a moment.
这项纪录毫无疑问将保持相当长一段时间！
Go ahead.
快上去
I count to three.
三二一
Glassman did not make it.
格拉斯曼死了
Cup did not make it. Put it out of your mind, Mac.
-卡普也死了 -忘掉他们吧，麦克
We die. No, we do not do that, Mac.
-我们都会死的 -不，我们不会的，麦克
They do not know where we are. They find us.
-他们不知道我们在哪 -他们会找到我们的
They can not see us.
他们怎么找得到？
Tell him to keep his mouth.
能不能让这家伙闭嘴？
Shut up. We're dying here.
-闭嘴 -我们要死在这了
Now Shut up, Mac.
行了，麦克，能别说了吗？
Mac chocolate.
嘿，麦克，巧克力
A piece of the evening and morning.
早晚各吃一片
Not?
听到没？
Two or three sips a day, right?
这个，一天只能喝几小口，知道吗？
Then it takes a while.
我们得靠这个活着
I'm glad it's you.
幸亏有你，我很欣慰
I am glad I am.
彼此彼此
What was that?
什么玩意儿？
Mac, search the flares.
麦克，麦克！快放信号！
Below.
我们在这儿！
Turn around.
快回来！
Dick, invert.
尼玛德！快回来！
What did you do, Mac?
你做了什么？麦克
It does not matter. Does it not matter?
-这无关紧要 -无关紧要？！这无关紧要？！
DAY 3
第三天
Grab him, Mac.
抓住它，麦克
I do not think I can.
这玩意我可不敢吃
We have to try.
没办法，不吃也得吃
We had to try it.
咱们一定得吃进去
You know what?Maybe the fish are not so picky.
要我说，如果是鱼的话没这么恶心
Good work, Phil.
干得好！菲尔
Right Here.
我来
Come here, Mac.
过来，麦克
Come on.
来啊
Is it good?
好吃吗？
The Japanese eat raw fish.
据说日本鬼子爱吃生鱼片
If you ask me,you do not eat before you cook it.
要我做菜的话，必定得先煮熟
A little lemon and a little garlic.
加一片柠檬和大蒜
When we get home,my mother will cook for you.
等我们回去后，让我妈做给你们吃
You know that article still in Life Magazine about Eddie Rickenbacker?
你有没有看过《生活》杂志上那篇关于埃迪·里肯巴克的文章？
He and his crew were without fuel over the Pacific Ocean.
他和他的船员在太平洋上没有燃料了
They drove around in 24 days rafts.
他们在救生船上呆了24天
24 days.
24天
But she survived, right?
但他们活下来了，是吗？
They were crazy.
是啊，最后差不多都疯了
But they made it.
但他们都活下来了
We need to keep talking not to lose our minds.
咱们得持续交谈，不能让脑子无意识
You know that I'm looking forward? Mama's gnocchi.
你知道我期待什么吗？我妈做的面团
Italians.
意大利特产
Nobody makes gnocchi like them.
我妈厨艺天下第一
They are so airy as clouds.
那面团如同云一般飘逸
First she makes the dough out of flour.
首先，她灵巧地揉面粉
Just as fine as talcum powder.
揉得跟飘柔般顺滑
Then they used at least a dozen eggs.
然后就是鸡蛋了，要至少一打鸡蛋
Then she gives them their thunder, Mac.
接着就开始像打雷那样打蛋，麦克，啪嗒啪嗒！啪嗒啪嗒！
On their thunder.
超强搅拌
Then pour over them there.
最后，浇在面团上
DAY 18
第18天
show me the way
我水尽山穷
The night is dark
黑夜中求索
and I am far from home
我远漂他乡
show me the way
问路在何方
Do you think God created the stars, Phil?
你觉得天上的星星是上帝创造的吗？菲尔
Yup.
是的吧
Do you think there some big plans ...
你有没有发现这儿给了我们很大的启示
we survived and others do not?
为什么其他人都死了，我们却活下来了？
Why are we here?
为什么我们现在会在这？
The plan is
这个启示就是
you have to live,as well as you can.
我们必须竭尽所能的活下去
You should try to have fun,on the way.
在沿途中你应该找点乐趣
And then one day it's over.
然后有一天结束了这种生活
So you wake up
当你醒来
and sees an angel sit beside the bed.
看见一个天使坐在床边
The angel says:
天使说：
"Now you may ask me all these stupid questions.
“你现在可以向我提请求，随便什么荒唐的都行”
I have all the answers. "
“我都能满足你”
Do you believe that?
你相信这些吗？
Yes, I believe that.
是的，我虔诚地相信
Our Father who is in heaven.Your name will be sanctified.
万能的上帝啊
If you help me through this, my prayers answered ...
如果您能助我渡过这场浩劫
I swear I dedicating my life to You.
我发誓会把一生都奉献给您
I'll do whatever you want.
用尽一生一世来将你供养
Please.
保佑我
Go ahead.
来了，来了，上吧！
You got it?
抓住没？
DAY 27
第27天
It's just a scratch.
这只是一个开始
How are things? It stinks.
-怎样？ -很臭
That is the connection, not you.
臭的是包扎带，不是你
We defeated Rickenbackers record four days ago.
我们四天前打破了里肯巴克的生存纪录
Do you like to know?
你还记天数了？
My God.
哦买噶
Go out, guys.
伙计们，快跳下去！快跳！
I'm still here.
麦克！菲尔！
If the Japanese are so bad we will win the war.
如果小日本都这么贱，我们会赢得这场战争的
Right Here.
给
He arranged for a surprise.
上帝安排了一个惊喜
He came down like a bomber.
他派了架轰炸机
Sharks gobbling distraught.
他派了虎视眈眈的鲨鱼
He saved your skinny ass.
他救了你的小命
1937. Best baseball player.
1937年，最优秀的棒球选手
A boy from Detroit.
底特律男孩
Gehringer.
格林格
Mac, join the game.
麦克，来玩游戏
I'm still here.
我一直在这
What do you make for breakfast, Zamp?
你早餐弄什么呢，格林格？
You tell me.
你告诉我
Gnocchi from your mother.
你妈做的面团
Gnocchi for breakfast?
早餐吃面团？
Why not?
不行吗？
I'm dying.
我快死了吗？
Perhaps, Mac.
可能吧，麦克
Tonight, you think?
你觉得会是今晚吗？
May Be.
可能吧
Tonight, I think.
我觉得就是今晚
If you made the dough,roll out.
如果你想做面团，就要滚面
Roll it out ...
一直滚
until it is smooth and smooth ...
直到它非常光滑
DAY 45
第45天
I have good news.
我有一个好消息
And bad news.
和一个坏消息
You alright?
你没事吧？
The country feels weird.
这什么鬼地方？
Weird.
的确是鬼子的地方
Shut up.
操你妈逼的！
Stop.
住手！
Please stop.
求你们住手。。。。
How many troops are in Hawaii?
夏威夷有多少人？
The colonel wants to know how many troops are in Hawaii.
大佐阁下想知道你们在夏威夷有多少军队
I do not know. Pick up.
-我母鸡 -快说！
I have not been there.
我从未去过夏威夷
Is he in this picture?
这个人，是你吗？
Is this you?
这是你吗？
Are you an Olympic athlete?
是个有名的奥林匹克运动员啊？
Are you a famous Olympic athlete?
你是一个有名的奥林匹克运动员吗？
Where the radar is in a B24E?
B-24E的雷达装在哪？
The colonel wants to know where radar is in a B24E.
大佐阁下想知道一架B-24E轰炸机的雷达装在哪个位置
We used the oldD models.
我们驾驶的是旧的B-24D型
Are you a bombardier?
你是投弹手吗？
What happened to Marines Makin Island?
马金岛的海军陆战队怎么样了？
Where is the northern bombs land?
诺登投弹瞄准器如何操作？
Press two buttons. What happened to the Marines?
只要按两个按钮，海军陆战队怎样了？
Sign the northern bombs site.
画出诺登投弹瞄准器的位置
They were beheaded.
他们都被斩首了
I drew a Philco radio with buttons on the side.
我画了两侧有按钮的菲戈收音机
Take off your clothes.
衣服脱光
On your knees.
跪下
On your knees?
跪下？
Are not we in Tokyo? Of Course.
-这里是东京吧？ -应该是
Here I would run a race during the Olympics.
本来我是要来这参加奥运会的
Before they were canceled.
后来他们不办了
I've always been wanting to go to Tokyo.
我一直想来东京的
Be careful what you wish for,buddy.
你梦想成真了，伙计
Soldier.
士兵！站这！
Officer.
军官！站那！
Soldier.Officer.
士兵！军官！
Good evening, old prisoners.
晚上好，老战俘们
Welcome new men.
欢迎，新战俘们
This is the detention center Omori.
这里是大森战俘收容所
I'm Corporal Watanabe.
我是伍长：渡边睦宏
You are enemies of Japan.
你们是大日本帝国的敌人
You will accordingly be treated.
你们会被处以极刑
Look at me.
看着我
Look me in the eyes.
看着我的眼睛
Do not look at me.
不准看我
New prisoners, you should not go.
新战俘们，你们没有自由
You are quarantined.
你们被隔离了
We can not use disorders in the camp.
在我这，不准有任何骚乱
Good evening, boys.Tom Miller, barrack commander.
晚上好，各位，我是汤姆·米勒，营房保长
I point you to the bunk beds.
我带你们去你们的床位
Do the top bunk.
上铺
You sleep here next to Sleeping Beauty.
你在这好好睡上一觉
Sit down.
坐下
307 you here.
307你过来这里
You are? Frank Tinker.
-你叫？ -弗兰克·廷克
Tinker, you take the top bunk.
廷克，你睡上铺
You've met the bird.
你们见识过“鸟人”的厉害了
Why do you call him the bird? Because he listens.
-为什么叫他“鸟人”？ -因为他耳朵很灵
When he heard we called him, he would kill us.
如果听到我们叫他名字，他会杀了我们
He comes from a rich family and wanted to be an officer.
他是个高富帅，想当一名军官
That was not approved,the matter went not so well.
没被批准，他就拿我们发泄
That explains his unpredictable behavior not.
这就是他不可理喻的原因
Commander Fitzgerald. Zamperini.
-我是菲茨杰拉德中校 -长官你好，我叫赞贝里尼
They want answers.
日本人拷问我们的人
That they do not get? Not one.
-有没有人屈打成招？ -没有
Try to get some sleep.
-好好睡一觉吧 -是，长官
There are many talents here in Omori.
我们大森战俘营，可谓是人才济济
We have an opera singer.Who is the opera singer?
我们这有个歌剧歌手，是谁来着？
We have a chef cook from Sydney Australia.
我们有个来自澳大利亚悉尼的厨师
We also have an Olympic athlete.
现在又有一个奥林匹克运动员
Who is the Olympic athlete?
谁是那个奥运会选手？
Stay down.
别站起来
You did not make it.
你输了
You are worth nothing.
你就是个二逼
He draws, so we can restore before the Japs find something.
由他绘图，我们要在日本人发现之前保存实力
He has the largest part of the war mapped.
最大的战况图
We are the Marshall Islands invaded.
我们在被入侵的马绍尔群岛
The United States Marshall Islands invaded.
美属马绍尔群岛
The allies are gaining ground.
盟军正节节胜利
For boys who eat nothing We shit a lot.
咱平时吃得最多的是什么？是屎
That is mine.
瞧，这坨是我的
I killed him. Then they shoot you.
-我真想杀了这帮畜生 -那他们也会杀了你
I do not care.
我可不在乎
Thus we not beat them.
这不算打败他们
We beat them by staying alive until the end of the war.
只有存活到战争结束我们才能算打败他们
So we do that.
这才是我们该做的
That is our revenge.
这才叫报仇
If I can, I make it.
“相信自己，就能取得胜利”
Exactly.
说得没错
That said my brother, Pete, always. He believed that I could do anything.
这话是我大哥皮特说的，他一直都相信我能成功
He thought I better was than I am.
一直都相信我能超越自我
Who says you're not?
谁说你不能？
We are approaching.
我军正步步逼近
Why have you forced me your store?
为什么你要逼我打你呢？
You're dead.
你已经死了
In America they say,that is Zamperini death.
在美国，他们说赞贝里尼已经死了
They have told your family, that you died in the war.
他们告诉你父母说你战死沙场
NBC Radio said to America
NBC广播电台公告全国：
"The famous Olympic rider Zamperini is dead.
著名奥运会长跑运动员赞贝利尼，死了
Do you want to tell your family,that you're not dead?
想不想告诉你的家人你还活着？
These gentlemen are from Radio Tokyo.
这两位先生来自东京广播电台
We have a program that can be heard around the world.
我们有一个向世界各地播放的节目
It's called 'The Postman Calls'.
叫做：“帝国好声音”
Hello, mother, your son is calling you.
“你好，妈妈，我是你的儿子”
Mother, I love you.
“妈妈，我爱你”
I am alive and make it right.
“我还活着，并且过得不错”
I'm just in my own words. Of Course.
-我只要说英语？ -当然
Hello, America.
你好，美国
This is 'The Postman Calls'.Today the postman rings
这里是“帝国好声音”，今天有一个好声音
to Mrs. Louise Zamperini in Torrance, California.
要传递给在加利福尼亚托兰斯的露易丝太太
Louie Zamperini is not missing or dead
令郎路易·赞贝里尼他并没有死，也没有失踪
as falsely claimed by your government.
是你的政府错误报道了他的死讯
He is safe and sound with us.
路易很安全，也很健康，他和我们在一起
Listen, Mrs. Zamperini, and do not thank us.
那么，露太太，请您别说话，用心去聆听
The pleasure is all on our side.
幸运女神永远站在我们这边
Hello, mother and father,sisters and friends.
你们好，爸爸妈妈，兄弟姐妹，父老乡亲们
Here you speak Louie.
我是你们的路易
For the first time in two years you hear my voice.
两年了你们第一次听到我的声音
I am unharmed and in good health.
我没受伤并且过得很好
I am now interned in a POW camp in Tokyo ...
我现在东京的一个战俘营
get treated so well as can be expected in wartime.
他们对我不错，我也许能幸存下来
I hope Pete every week on visit may come from San Diego.
我希望皮特每周能从圣地亚哥去看你们
Dad, take good care of my guns ...
爸爸，看好我的枪
so we can go hunting,when I get home.
我回家后还要和您一块去打猎呢
And what rabbits can shoot for mommies gnocchi sauce.
去打几只兔子给妈妈做面团
Merry Christmas and Happy New Year to you all.
祝你们圣诞快乐，新年快乐
Your loving son Louie.
爱你们的儿子：路易
You were very good.
很好，你说得很好
You need to talk on the radio again.
你得再说一回
BROADCAST SCRIPT
广播稿
This I can not say. Why not?
-这我不能说 -为啥不能？
Because it is a lie.
因为这些都不是真的
I can not say what there it is about America.
我不能说这些关于美国的事
They have said it.Americans like you.
那几个已经说了，跟你一样也是美国人
They live here quite comfortably.
他们在这过得很舒适
Good food.
有吃有喝
They get great food.
这里有美味佳肴
Would you go back to the camp?
难道你想回战俘营？
Say it on the radio.
还是老实念广播稿吧
You're just like me.
你和我很像
We are both strong.
我们脾气都很倔
I saw it in your eyes the first day.
你刚进来那天我就从你眼中看到了
I thought:This man is my friend.
当时我就在想：这哥们我交定了
But the Japanese enemy.
但是，你是大日本帝国的敌人
You're not listening.
你不听讯问
You do not do what you asked.
不肯说实话
Respect is needed.
尊重是必须的
Without respect, no order.
没有尊重就没有秩序
This man needs to learn to respect.
这人需要学学怎么尊重别人
All other prisoners should teach him that.
所有其他战俘都应该教教他
Every prisoner has the man beat in the face.
每一个战俘打这人的脸
We can not do.
伍长阁下，我们不能这么做
Do it.
打吧
Hit him in the face.
快给我打他的脸
Beat him.
打他！
Next. Come on.
-下一个！ -来吧
Turn hard. Come on, hit me.
-用力打！ -快啊！揍我！
Next.
下一个！
Hit me hard, Tink.
来吧，廷克，狠劲打我
Come on.
来吧
Next.
下一个！
Turn hard.
用力！
Where's that naughty little worm?Have you seen her, buddy?
这条懒虫跑哪去了？看到她了吗？哥们？
There you are, lazy girl.How should I get ready for the ball ...
你在这儿呢！懒鬼！你什么都不做我还怎么去参加舞会？
if you do nothing? You just so little use if our dance classes.
你压根就不会跳舞，所以干脆就别去了
Make my dress so baron Hillebrandt I notice.
把我的裙子整好一点，要高端大气上档次
Nobody notices you, even though you fall in their lap. Do my hair.
就算你参加了舞会，也没人会关注像你这样的挫逼，整理一下我的头发
Make my dress.Do my hair.
-整理下我的裙子，裙子裙子裙子 -整理下我的头发，头发头发头发
Her. I speak now Prussian?
她是普鲁士人吗？
You leave me all these stupid impossible things do without food or rest.
你们把所有的蠢事都留给我做，却不让我吃饭和睡觉
You lock me up in a rabbit hutch. I am fed up.
你们把我锁在窝棚里，我可受够了！
I have good news.
我有个好消息
I obtained my doctorate.
我升职了
That's the good news.
这是好消息
The bad news?
而坏消息是
I have to say goodbye to my friends.
我得和朋友们说沙扬娜拉了
I leave tomorrow Omori.
我明天就要离开这儿了
Stay cool and your heart in the right place ...
保持冷静，放松心态
then you can do anything.
然后你就无所不能
Fear not, dear child.I'm your fairy godmother.
别怕，乖孩子，我是你的神仙教母
You can congratulate me.
不祝贺一下我吗？
And so it goes.
他走了
Just like that.
就这么走了
I have four kings.
我四个老K
Here You Go.
走你
The baron has lost Tinker.Then there is sugar for us tonight.
男爵赌输了廷克，今晚我们便有糖吃了
Miller?Do you have a bucket?
米勒？你有水桶吗？
We help the Japs?Let it burn.
帮鬼子干吗？让它烧去吧
Pass it on.
传过去
B49 boys.
是B-29轰炸机，伙计们！
Now it takes no more long. Restrain your enthusiasm.
-我们就快得救了？ -我得说几句
If the Allies win
一旦盟军赢了
shoot the Japs us all dead.
鬼子会把我们都杀了
I've heard them say.
我听他们说过这事
If we win, we're dead.
盟军赢了，我们就完蛋了
Where should we pray for?
那我们该祈求什么呢？
Lie down.
小心！卧倒！
Get your stuff.They move us.
拿上东西，他们要咱们换个位置
Where To? Towards a new camp.
-去哪儿？ -不知道，去个新营
Tokyo Ritz. a place where the Allies could not find us.
一个盟军永远也找不到咱们的地方
This is Naoetsu detention.
这里是直江津集中营
I'm Sergeant Watanabe,your commander.
我是渡边中尉，你们的指挥官
You are enemies of Japan.
你们是大日本帝国的敌人
And accordingly be treated.
就自然要受到这样的对待
You will help the Japanese by working in the coal mines.
你们要去挖煤，以此为帝国效力
Anyone who refuses to work
如果有谁胆敢不干活
is executed.
他就会被处决
Why are you looking at me?
你干嘛不看着我？
You can sleep here.
你睡那儿
You two there.
你们两个，那儿
It ends here, friends.Nobody knows you're here.
一切都结束了，伙计们，没人会知道我们在这儿
Reconcile but your destiny.
保持顺从，但坚定信念
Your President Roosevelt
你们的总统，罗斯福
is dead.
已经死了
You alright?
你还好吧？
Pick up.
捡起来！
Up.
抬头
Up over your head.
抬起你的脑袋
If losing him,shoot him down.
如果他敢跑就开枪
Come on, Louie. Come on, buddy.
-加油，路易 -加油，伙计
Do not look at me.
不准看着我
Prisoners Naoetsu.
直江津的战俘们
The war is over.
战争，结束了
Today, in the spirit of the new future our mighty nation
今天，在大日本帝国伟大精神的感召下
We invite all the prisoners
我们邀请所有战俘
to bathe in the river Hokura.
在小仓河沐浴
Now it's over.
这么说的话。。。
It's over with us.
我们死定了？
These are our boys. They saw us.
-那是我们的飞机！ -他们看见我们了！
The war is over.
战争结束了！！
HERE TO SELL
物资空投点
God, look at you sometimes.
感谢上帝！你终于回来了！
Dear mother.
亲爱的妈妈！
In 1946, Louie Zamperini married his heroine Cynthia Applewhite.
路易·赞贝里尼与辛西娅·阿普尔怀特于1946年喜结连理
They had a daughter, Cissy,and a son, Luke.
育有一女叫茜茜，一子叫卢克
Lieutenant Russell Phil Phillips survived and married his Cecy.
罗塞尔·菲尔·菲利普斯中尉活了下来并和西塞莉结了婚
He and Louie remained friends long after the war.
他与路易的友谊延续至战争结束以后
Mutsuhiro Watanabe, "bird", lived long as underground war criminal ...
渡边睦宏，“鸟人”，战后一直躲藏着，几年后其罪行被揭露
until the US granted him amnesty as part of the reconciliation with Japan.
作为与日本和解的一部分，美国赦免了他
Louie suffered hose posttraumatic stress disorder.
经过多年的精神和肉体创伤后遗症
He came after his promise to God,when his life was saved.
路易实践了当年对上帝许下的信仰承诺
By faith taught that the way Louie forward was not revenge, but forgiveness.
在信仰的激励下，路易选择了宽恕而非复仇
He went back to Japan and sought the kidnappers and reconciled with them.
他返回日本，试图与当年战俘营的看守们和解
Only the bird refused to meet him.
只有“鸟人”拒绝见他
Louie finally saw his dream fulfilled to run again at the Olympics.
路易最终实现了他的梦想：再次在奥运会上奔跑
at 80yearold.
在自己的耄耋之年
In Japan.
在日本